Timothy Proctor

Email: <u>Tim.Proctor@Live.com</u> | Website: <u>www.timproctor.co.nz</u>

GitHub: Tim-Proctor / TimProctorAUT (Uni) DOB: 12 / 08 / 1998

My name is Tim; I am an aspiring software developer. I have always had an interest in computers and started learning to program at the age of eleven when I tried to make a small computer game. This interest grew into wanting to make software development my career.

Skills:

Technical Skills:

Languages:

- JavaScript with React
- HTML and CSS
- PHP
- Java
- Nodeis
- SQL
- Python
- Dart

Frameworks and Methodologies:

- Xamarin
- Flutter
- Agile Methodologies (SCRUM and KANBAN)

Tools:

- VS Code and VS Studio (2013, 2016, 2017)
- GIT Bash and GitHub
- GitHub Desktop
- MySQL Workbench
- PuTTY
- WinSCP
- Windows and Linux CLI
- Microsoft Office

Other Skills and Knowledge:

- Some Academic Cisco Networking Experience
- Understanding of ITIL and COBIT
- Experience with Mobile App Development
- Academic experience with Database Design and Development

Planning and Organisation Skills:

I have always made it a priority to keep myself on top of all due dates for my workload. For example, in my third year of university, while working on a full year mobile development project, I also had course work for Python based Text Recognition script that I needed to write as well as a React and Nodejs based Web app. These all required me to learn new syntaxes and libraries which meant that I needed to be extremely organised in how much time I would give to each project. I planned out a workflow, that gave me time to learn the new syntax, library, and language.

Problem Solving:

I enjoy finding solutions to problems; I enjoy the challenge of being put in a situation where I need to adapt and overcome errors or issues and find possible work arounds. I find that this is a regular occurrence when it comes to programming which has led me to learn more programming languages and syntaxes.

Communication Skills:

I am confident in taking and providing criticism; I am open to changes that may need to be made and I'm not frightened to take the lead in a situation if needed. I have experience working in a professional relationship with a client.

SCRUM and Agile Methodology Knowledge:

I have been trained and have experience in using Agile Methodologies like SCRUM and KANBAN. During University a large area of education was development processes and frameworks that are used in the industry. We were introduced to Agile methodologies and were expected to complete multiple internal projects following these frameworks. Also, for the final project when we had to complete a project for a real-world client, SCRUM was our framework of choice. During that project for the first half I was SCRUM Master which was the role in which someone will ensure processes of the framework are being followed.

Education:

Auckland University of Technology (AUT):

Jan 2017 to Dec 2019

Qualifications:

 Bachelor Computer and Information Science, Majoring in Software Development, 2019

Green Bay High School:

Jan 2012 to Dec 2016

Qualifications:

NCEA Level 1 with Excellence, 2014

- NCEA Level 2, 2015
- NCEA Level 3 with Excellence, 2016
- NCEA Level 3, Digital Technologies Programming with Merit, 2016

Awards:

- Top in Subject Digital Technologies (Programming) Level 2, 2015
- Top in Subject Digital Technologies (Programming) Level 3, 2016
- The Trusts Community Foundation Award, 2016

Work Experience:

AUT Work Experience (Lifespan Trust)

Jan 2019 to Nov 2019

Team Developer / SCRUM Leader:

During the last year of university we were expected to complete a paper called Research and Development where you were given a team, a real world client, and were expected to independently undertake and manage a project for a client with one mentor selected from the AUT Staff to support our group.

Our project was to work with a client Lifespan Trust where we needed to develop an android application. For the project we developed the app using Google's multiplatform framework 'Flutter' this was so that the client could easily port the application over to IOS in the future. We used SCRUM an Agile Methodology to facilitate the project.

All members were expected to develop portions of the app, and the SCRUM Leader role meant that I would operate Team Daily Standups and Ensure we were completing all expected SCRUM Processes that we had selected.

This application was completed at the end of the year, and as a team we produced a website that the client could use to download the app while they waited to organise setting up the app for the google play store. This app was release under the name 'Nap Optimizer' and is currently available on the google play store.

- Mobile Development with Flutter Framework
- Dart Programming
- Following and Managing Agile Processes.
- o Communicate with a Client
- Operate professional Meetings.
- Creating Supporting Document for a project i.e. Project Briefs/ Project
 Proposals

NZ Uniforms

Sales Assistant, December 2017 – October 2018.

Dec 2017 to April 2019

I started working at NZ Uniforms at the New Lynn Branch full time during University summer break. I worked from Monday to Saturday, initially as a Stock Runner but then I quickly moved into a floor Sales Assistant roll and finally to a Point of Sales Assistant operating the. I later managed the store on Saturdays by myself and also assisted the Store Manager during the week on days I was free. My roles tasks included:

- Stocking Shelves
- Heavy Lifting
- Processing Web Orders
- Assisting Customers
- o Taking Customer Phone Calls
- Processing Sales
- EFPOS and Cash Handling.
- o Daily Banking and Accounts
- o Opening and Closing the Store
- Independently managing and operating a store.
- Using POS and CRM Software ACT and Accredo.

Assistant Manager, October 2018 - April 2019

- o Assisting in Training New Team Members.
- Ability to manage a team of 2-3 staff members.
- Helping with defusing situations involving difficult customers.
- Relaying Expected Daily Sales goals to team members

CMI Springs

Dispatch Temp Worker.

Dec 2016 to Jan 2017

- Packing products into Boxes and bags while counting to make sure there is a correct amount in each.
- o Re-stocking Shelves and Collecting Stock to Pack from said shelves.
- o Heavy Lifting.
- Working with different equipment like Hydraulic Presses and CNC machine.
- Using palette trolley.

Hobbies and Interests:

Guitar:

I have been learning to play guitar since I was seven years old. I current focus on playing on Classical Guitar and am learning to sight-read sheet music.

Camping:

I enjoy camping with friends and family or just myself. I find that taking some time to enjoy the countryside to be relaxing and great in helping clear my head.

Dungeons and Dragon:

I meet up with a group of friends to play, this cooperative roleplaying game where we must solve problems and adapt to changes while working as a team.

References:

For Privacy, References details have been removed from the CV please contact me via my email, for these references.